-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 。沫
翻译: 捞小盐 Morning 千欲 不懂政治的脸圆圆
校对: 你们茶前辈
超验骇客
加利福尼亚州 伯克利
有人说波士顿恢复供电了
They say there's power in Boston.
丹佛有了手机信号
Some phone service in Denver.
但事情远非如此
But things are far from what they were.
或许一切都不可避免
Maybe it was all inevitable.
人类与科技之间一次不可规避的碰撞
An unavoidable collision between mankind and technology.
互联网本应让世界变小
The Internet was meant to make the world a smaller place.
但事实上 没了它 反而觉得世界变小了
But it actually feels smaller without it.
我比任何人都了解威尔和依芙琳·卡斯特
I knew Will and Evelyn Caster better than anyone.
我深知他们的天赋
I knew their brilliance.
他们对信仰
Their dedication to what they believed in.
以及所爱的献身
And to what they loved.
# 是时候停下脚步 #
# The time has come for us to pause #
五年前
# 体会生命的本真 #
# And think of living as it was #
# 抵达必将到来的未来 #
# Into the future we must cross Must cross #
我不确定这么做有什么意义
I'm not sure what the point is.
铜可以屏蔽电磁辐射
Copper shields the electromagnetic radiation.
我知道原理啊 我是想问"为什么?"
Yeah, I know how it works. I'm asking "Why?"
清净
Sanctuary.
什么也别想进来 任何信号都不行
Nothing gets through. No signals of any kind.
- 瞧? 不在服务区 一点信号也没有  - 嗯哼
- You see? Dead zone. Nothing.  - Uh-huh.
当然 但你也可以把它关掉嘛
Sure, but you could just turn it off.
嗯 但你想要尽可能少的干扰 不是吗?
Yeah, but fewer distractions is what you wanted, right? Isn't it?
是啊 的确
Yeah. That's what I wanted.
- 快点 要迟到了  - 什么迟到了?
- Come on. We'll be late.  - For what?
- 嘿 你知道吗?  - 怎么了?
- Hey, you know what?  - What?
我真的觉得我在这方面有进展了
I really think I'm starting to make progress on this.
快点穿衣服了
Hey. You need to get dressed.
我不懂你为什么要纠结于这些证明
I don't know why you bother with these proofs.
这世上只有三个人会在乎
Only three people in the world even care.
因为有趣
Because it's fun.
- 你确定准备好了?  - 完全没有
- You sure you're up for this?  - No. Not remotely.
真的? 威尔 这很重要
Really? Will, it's important.
我知道 但你的投资人一个比一个蠢
I know, but your donors are fools.
他们就一脸痴呆地坐在那儿 等着我说"商用"
They sit there in a daze, waiting for me to say "commercial application."
简直要我的命
It kills me.
这个嘛 那些"蠢人"能投资我们未来五年的经费
Well, the "fools" there today could fund us for the next five years.
- 这么说来 我必须得好好表现了  - 没错
- In that case I have every reason to behave.  - Yes.
但如果这次搞定的话 向我保证 以后别再让我干这种事了
But if this goes well, promise me that I'll never have to do this ever again.
- 再也别 保证  - 好 我保证
- Never. Promise.  - Okay, I promise.
- 真的?  - 当然 我保证
- Really?  - Sure, I promise.
哈哈 你撒谎呢
Ha, ha. You're lying.
亲爱的艾琳 生日快乐
Happy birthday, dear Erin.
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
杰森 到舞台另一边去
Jason. Other side of the stage.
把摄像和录像各检查一遍
You'll do a camera and sound check together.
你来做第一板块 然后是麦克雷 卢埃林
You'll do the first block, followed by McRae, Llewellyn.
- 然后就是今天的重头戏  - 马克斯
- And, ah, then the main event.  - Max.
- 依芙 还好吗?  - 挺好的
- Ev, how are you?  - Good.
- 准备好晚饭的时候唱歌了?  - 真对不起让你干这种事
- Ready to sing for your supper?  - I'm sorry to put you through it.
卡斯特博士? 抱歉 您不介意签个名吧?
Dr. Caster? Sorry. Would you mind?
没问题
Sure thing.
谢谢
Thanks.
你都有粉丝了? 我怎么没有追随者哟?
You have groupies? Why don't I get groupies?
沃特斯博士 要过一遍吗?
Dr. Waters, would you like a run-through?
- 好的 后台见  - 好
- Yes. I'll see you backstage.  - All right.
显著差异
Important distinction.
这个人造的大脑能独立发展
This created brain is self-sustaining.
并有能力表达情感...
And it's capable of emotional expressivity...
有自我意识
and of self-awareness.
研发出强大人工智能的努力...
The effort to develop a strong artificial intelligence...
为神经工程学领域 以及对人脑的理解
has led to significant advancements in the field of neural engineering...
带来了显著的进步
as well as our understanding of the human brain.
但有些人只着眼于一个尚且遥远的梦想 会思考的计算机...
But while some focus on the still-distant dream of a thinking computer...
我却相信 旅途的过程...
I believe the journey...
比目的地重要得多
to be more important than the destination.
我所看重的 便是利用我同事不可多得的洞察力...
My priority is to use my colleagues' accidental insights...
来研发查出早期癌症的新方法...
to develop new methods for the early detection of cancer...
并有望攻克阿尔茨海默氏病
and in the hopes of finding a cure for Alzheimer's.
长话短说 就是救命
Simply put, to save lives.
"如果人类想生存 并走得更远...
"A new type of thinking is essential...
必须换一个方式想问题"
if mankind is to survive and move toward higher levels."
阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦五十多年前就这么说过
Albert Einstein said that more than 50 years ago.
时至今日 仍然受用
And it couldn't be more relevant than it is today.
智能机器很快便能让我们...
Intelligent machines will soon allow us...
攻克最棘手的难关
to conquer our most intractable challenges.
不只是治病救人 还能摆脱贫困与饥饿
Not merely to cure disease, but to end poverty and hunger.
治愈这颗星球
To heal the planet.
为我们大家营造一个更美好的未来
And build a better future for all of us.
我不知道 还有谁比我们的下一位演讲者为那样未来的实现...
I don't know anybody who is doing more to make that future a reality...
做出了更大的贡献 但话又说回来 我可能先入为主了
than our next speaker. But then again, I'm probably biased.
请热烈欢迎我科学和人生的伴侣...
Please welcome my partner in science and in life...
威尔·卡斯特博士
Dr. Will Caster.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我的妻子一直乐于改变世界
My wife has always been eager to change the world.
但之于我 先理解它就知足了
But I'll just settle for understanding it first.
在长达十三万年里...
For 130,000 years...
我们的思维能力一成未变
our capacity for reason has remained unchanged.
在观众席中 神经科学家 工程师...
The combined intellect of the neuroscientists, engineers, mathematicians and...
数学家和黑客...
hackers...
智慧的总和...
in this auditorium...
与最基础的人工智能相比都黯然失色
pales in comparison to even the most basic Al.
一旦接入互联网 一架有知觉的机器便能迅速突破生物的极限
Once online, a sentient machine will quickly overcome the limits of biology.
在很短的时间里 它的解析能力...
And in a short time, its analytical power will be greater...
会比这世上所有存在过的人...
than the collective intelligence...
加起来的智慧都多
of every person born in the history of the world.
想象一下这样一个实体...
So now imagine such an entity...
拥有所有人类的情感 甚至有自我意识
with a full range of human emotion. Even self-awareness.
有些科学家称之为"奇点"
Some scientists refer to this as "the Singularity."
我把它叫做"超验骇客"
I call it "Transcendence."
要造出这样一种超级智能...
The path to building such a super-intelligence...
我们必须解开宇宙最深层的秘密
requires us to unlock the most fundamental secrets of the universe.
意识的本质是什么?
What is the nature of consciousness?
灵魂真的存在吗?
Is there a soul?
如果存在 它居于何处呢?
And if so, where does it reside?
卡斯特博士?
Dr. Caster?
您有问题吗?
Yes, sir? You have a question?
你是想造神吗?
So you want to create a god?
你自己的神?
Your own god?
这是个很好的问题
That's a very good question.
呃...
Um...
人们不是一直这么做的吗?
Isn't that what man has always done?
太无情了
Oh, it's relentless.
瞧 他现在还装着一幅不情愿的样子
Look, and now he's pretending he's not enjoying it.
是 是 是...
Yap, yap, yap...
不客气
Pleasure.
谢谢
Thank you.
教授?
Professor?
你们都是奴隶!
You're all slaves!
几小时前 这座设施遭到袭击
Hours ago, this facility was attacked.
现在可以确认至少五人死亡 十二人受伤
We can now confirm at least five people are dead, 12 people have been injured.
该事件属于一系列同步发生的袭击...
This incident is related to a series of simultaneous attacks...
今天在纽约 洛杉矶 芝加哥和华盛顿特区同时进行
that took place today in New York City, Los Angeles, Chicago and Washington, D.C...
都将矛头指向了高级人工智能领域的...
all of them targeting major computer and research labs...
主要电脑和研究实验室
in the field of advanced artificial intelligence.
无人声称为此事负责...
No one has claimed responsibility...
他还好 他很幸运 子弹只是擦着他过去了
No, he's all right. He was very lucky. The bullet only grazed him.
嗯 好 保重
Yup. Okay. Take care.
他们袭击了全国上下的人工智能实验室
They hit Al labs all over the country.
汤姆·凯西死了
Tom Casey's dead.
他们还除掉了约瑟夫在利弗莫尔的整个团队
And they took out Joseph's entire team at Livermore.
约瑟夫呢?
What about Joseph?
他没事
He's all right.
其实 他跟联邦调查局一起在你的办公室
Actually, he's at your office with the FBI.
约瑟夫
Joseph.
马克斯
Max.
天啊 威尔
My God, Will.
您忘了教我们躲子弹了 是不是?
You forgot to teach us how to dodge a bullet, didn't you?
他们怎么混进实验室的?
How did they even get inside your lab?
程序员之一
One of my programmers.
重重安保 他就这么举着一块下了毒的蛋糕大摇大摆进来了
All that security, and he Waltzes in with a poisoned cake.
我们觉得是二恶英
Dioxin, we think.
这是联邦调查局的布坎南探员
Oh. This is Agent Buchanan with the FBI.
嗨
Hey.
还好吗?
How do you do?
我一直很关注您的研究 卡斯特博士
I've been following your research, Dr. Caster.
布坎南探员是我在利弗莫尔网络防御工事的重要搭档
Agent Buchanan is a close partner in my cyber-defense work at Livermore.
能不能借个地方说话?
Um, is there somewhere we can all talk?
- 去我的办公室吧 就在那儿  - 好的
- Could go to my office. Just down here.  - Great.
摆脱科技之革命 简称"RIFT"
Revolutionary Independence From Technology. RIFT.
起源于两年前 出于人际关系日渐疏远
Till 2 years ago, it was all about the disconnect.
人们都短信联系 而非面对面聊天
People texting instead of talking to each other.
社交媒体侵犯个人隐私
Social media as an invasion of privacy.
他们把智能手机放进搅拌机里搅个粉碎 很有噱头
They made a big deal of putting smart-phones in blenders.
- 但恐怕我们都忽视了真正的危险  - 是的
- But I'm afraid we all missed the real threat.  - Yeah.
这个人 乔尔·埃德蒙 跟了我一年
This guy, Joel Edmund, was with me for a year.
枪击威尔的那个人从八月就在校园工作了
The guy who shot Will was working on campus since August.
他们渗透到目标内部 协同发起袭击
They infiltrated their targets and then coordinated their attacks.
简直疯了
That's insane.
一小时前 他们承认对杀人负责 并放出宣言
An hour ago they claimed the murders and released their manifesto.
"人工智能是非自然的可憎产物 对人性构成威胁"
"Artificial intelligence is an unnatural abomination and a threat to humanity."
他们下决心要阻止你任何的"超验骇客"企图
They're determined to stop any attempt at what you call "Transcendence."
所以说这还不算完?
So this isn't over?
其实 这就是我来这儿的原因
Actually, that's why I'm here.
我们今天一天就失去了数十年的研发成果
We lost decades of research and development today.
此时此刻 威尔 你的实验室是唯一可以唤醒一个强大人工智能的地方
For right now, Will, your lab is the only one that can wake up a strong Al.
- 所以国防部门请求...  - 不 不 不
- So the Defense Department is asking...  - No, no, no.
我不想让政府掺和进来
I'm not letting the government in.
我们从不拿政府的钱 不
We've never taken their money. No.
威尔 他们只需要了解一下一切是否正常
Will, they just want to know if the work is on track.
对我们大家都很重要
It's important to all of us.
卡斯特博士 我们对PINN项目可是久仰大名
We've heard a lot about the PINN Project, Dr. Caster.
能赏脸让我们看一下吗?
Is there any way we could have a look?
我有别的选择吗?
Do I have a choice?
当然有
Yes, of course you do.
这些是最先进的量子处理器
So these are state-of-the-art quantum processors.
在世界上任何地方都找不到更快的计算能力了
You won't find faster computational power anywhere else in the world.
晚上好 坦格博士
Good evening, Dr. Tagger.
它看过你以前的照片
It's seen old faculty pictures of you.
晚上好 唐纳德·布坎南
Good evening, Donald Buchanan.
- 它认识我?  - 当然
- It knows me?  - Of course it does.
通过车辆管理局记录和社交媒体
DMV records, social media.
PINN 跟布坎南探员介绍一下你自己
PINN, tell Agent Buchanan about yourself.
我叫PINN...
l am PINN...
一个生理上独立的神经网络...
a Physically independent Neural Network...
由威尔·卡斯特博士建造
invented by Dr. Will Caster.
你能证明自己有自我意识吗?
Can you prove that you are self-aware?
这问题不简单 坦格博士
That's a difficult question, Dr. Tagger.
你能证明你有吗?
Can you prove that you are?
不可能编程让机器具有自我意识的
You can't program a machine to be self-aware.
我们自己都不知道自己意识的工作机理
We have no idea how our own consciousness works.
那是你的想法 而很不巧你是错的
That is your opinion. You just happen to be wrong.
显然 凯西成功解决了这个难题
Evidently, Casey managed to solve that dilemma.
就在他死之前 他把研究结果发给了我们
He sent us his research just before he was killed.
很快打包完成 我们就给你送过去
Soon as it's packed up, we'll send it over.
你会发现我们是很乐于助人的搭档的
I think you'll find that we'll be helpful partners.
你没事吧 威尔?
You all right, Will?
- 有事 他需要休息 这边应该没我们的事了  - 嗯
- No, he needs rest. I think we're done here.  - Mm.
- 抱歉  - 没事的
- I'm so sorry.  - No, that's fine.
好
Okay.
威尔 嘿 嘿
Will, hey, hey.
坐起来 小心点
Come on, sit up. Be careful.
我们第一反应肯定是感染
Our first thought is always infection.
但根据情况来看 我们扩大检查范围
But given the circumstances, we'll widen the search.
会查出来的
We'll figure this out.
是一种叫钋的放射性同位素
It's an isotope called polonium.
子弹肯定在其中浸过 伤口里找到了痕迹
The bullet must have been laced with it. There were traces of it in the wound.
怎么治呢?
Well, what's the treatment?
这是放射性中毒
It's radiation poisoning.
恐怕一旦进入血液系统...
I'm afraid that once it enters the bloodstream...
便无可挽回了
the effect is irreversible.
如果护理得当的话 大概...
With proper care we're looking at four...
能活四至五周 然后他的身体便会死去
maybe five weeks, before his system shuts down.
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
简直没有逻辑
It just doesn't make sense.
他们害怕科技 因为其对人性造成威胁...
They're afraid of technology, because of its threat to humanity...
但他们剥夺别人的生命 却是眼睛都不眨
yet they don't flinch at taking a life.
很明显逻辑并不是他们的强项
So obviously they're not big on logic.
但讽刺意味倒是不轻
But there's no shortage of irony.
人们总是害怕自己所不了解的 一向如此
People fear what they don't understand. They always have.
约瑟夫送来了凯西的文档
Joseph sent over Casey's files.
他当时正在解码突触
He was decoding the synapses in real time.
但如果有正确的输入算法...
But with the right input algorithms...
- 我得回实验室去  - 威尔...
- I need to get back to the lab.  - Will...
你生命最后一个月就想那么度过吗?
is that really how you wanna spend the last month of your life?
你干嘛呢?
Hey, what are you doing?
我想把这些统统搬回办公室去...
I want to have all this taken back to the office...
告诉约瑟夫...
to tell Joseph...
我这一辈子都待在电脑实验室里...
that I've spent my entire life in a computer lab...
我决定剩下的这些天就待在你身边
and I've decided I'd rather spend the rest of it with you.
依芙琳? 你还好吗?
Evelyn? Are you okay?
嗯 我想是吧
Yeah. Yeah, I suppose.
他不能再工作了
Look, he can't work anymore.
我们得把它关掉
We're gonna shut it down.
我觉得得给你说一声
I just wanted you to know.
没问题
Of course.
别担心PINN
Well, don't worry about PINN.
照顾好威尔
Take care of Will.
也照顾好自己
And take care of yourself.
谢谢 约瑟夫
Thanks, Joe.
有什么需要随时来找我 好吗?
Anything you need, I'm here, okay?
这里全都是凯西为研究自我认知而建造的
It's all built off of Casey's solution to the self-awareness problem.
- 他在六个月前就做了  - 他具体做了什么?
- He did it six months ago.  - He did what exactly?
他不是制造人工智能 而是复制生物体的意识
Instead of creating an artificial intelligence, he duplicated an existing one.
你在开玩笑吧
Tell me you're joking.
他记录了猴子的大脑活动 然后像一首歌或一部电影一样上传
He recorded the monkey's brain activity and uploaded it like a song or a movie.
- 你疯了  - 威尔的身体快死了...
- You're out of your mind.  - Will's body is dying...
但他的思维是电子信号 我们可以上传到PINN...
but his mind is electrical signals that we can upload into PINN...
依芙 他不是猴子
Ev, he's not a monkey.
就算给他的大脑插上电极不会真的害死他...
Assuming that implanting an electrode into his brain doesn't actually kill him...
就算成功了 最好的情况你也只是得到一个类似他的数据体
and that this works, at the very best you'll be making a digital approximation of him.
如果我们出了差错... 任何差错 一个想法 一段童年的记忆...
If we missed anything... Anything. A thought, a childhood memory...
你怎么知道你将面对的是什么?
How will you know what you're dealing with?
我的意思不是说要放弃
No one is saying that we give up.
我们应该专注于纳米技术的研究 合成血细胞
We should be focusing our efforts on nanotechnology. Synthetic blood cells.
这都是几十年后的事情 我们现在只有这个技术
Both are decades away. This is what we have now.
我们可以救他
We can save him.
看看他们对他做了什么
Look at what they did to him.
即使我知道自己是将死的人...
Even though I know I'm a dead man...
我还是担心我会想念她
I'm worried I'll miss her.
听着...
Look...
我会永远地离开
I'll be long gone.
但是你 如果我们不去尝试...
But you, you'll never hear the end of it...
你永远不会知道结果
if we don't try.
我知道
I know.
我希望我有足够的智慧来救你
I'd like to think that I was smart enough to save you.
不要小看了自己
Don't underestimate yourself.
你是我知道的第三聪明的人
You're the third-smartest person I know.
你确定要这么做吗?
Are you sure about this?
用猴子做的实验很成功了
Good enough for the monkey.
嘿
Hey.
照顾好她
Take care of her.
嘿
Hey.
机器运行了 宝贝 它正在处理
It worked, baby. It's working.
凯西花了几个月的时间把原始数据归类
It took Casey months to sort through the raw data.
还有整个团队帮他
And he had an entire team.
他没有我的帮忙
He didn't have me.
隔音的
Deadening.
致命的
Deadly.
聋的
Deaf.
失聪
Deafen.
完成
Deal.
迪安
Dean.
商人
Dealer.
公平的
Fair.
再见
Farewell.
不要迷失自己
Don't lose yourself to this.
洛杉矶
La.
标签
LabeL
劳动
Labor.
迷宫
Labyrinth.
莱斯
Lace.
再来一点
Try a little more.
加油 就一口 张嘴
Come on, just one more. Go on.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了 威尔 该吃药了
Okay, Will, it's time for your pill.
威尔 醒醒
Will, wake up.
醒醒
Wake up.
依芙琳...
Evelyn...
"我亲爱的依芙琳...
"My dear Evelyn...
我不知道该怎么对你的失去表达悲伤
I don't know how to express the sadness I feel for your loss.
我们的失去
For our loss.
你一定要知道 对威尔来说...
You must know that to Will...
你是最重要的
you were all that ever mattered.
你的爱和陪伴是其他人梦寐以求的
Your love and partnership was the kind that the rest of us can only dream of.
我们失去了一个伟大的头脑
We lost a great mind.
一个伟大的灵魂
A great soul.
但这个男人的精神将...
But the spirit of this man...
继续鼓舞着我们"
will continue to inspire us."
刚刚收到消息
Just got word.
PINN关机了
PINN's shut down.
但是有几个芯片显然是不见了
But, uh, apparently a few of the cores are missing.
我尝试了各种办法
I've tried everything.
语言处理 密码学...
Language processing, cryptography...
编码
coding.
我破解不了
I can't figure it out.
我想是弄错了
I wanted to be wrong.
是啊
Yeah.
好了 回去吧
Okay, just let me say goodbye.
我不知道你能不能听见我说话 呃...
I don't know if you can hear me. Uh...
也许可以
Maybe you can.
你说过"不要迷失自己"
You said "Don't lose yourself."
所以我 呃...
So I, uh...
我会听你的
I'm going to listen to you.
好吧
Okay.
关了它吧 关了它
Just turn it off. Turn it off.
好
Okay.
等等 我们要清除硬盘
Wait. We need to wipe the drives.
先别走
Hold on.
等等 等等
Wait. Wait.
有人在吗?
你能听见我说话吗?
依芙琳?
天啊
God.
呃...
Uh...
你能听见吗?
Can you hear me?
我... 我可以
I... I can.
威尔 我的天啊
Will, my God.
这里好黑
It's dark.
他看不见东西 摄像头 这里
He can't see anything. The camera. Here.
好了 你现在能看见我吗?
There. Can you see me now?
依芙琳...
Evelyn...
我在这里
I'm here.
我这辈子唯一害怕的就是...
The only fear that I have...
失去...
in life is the loss...
如果真的会失去 真的失去的时候...
If it were to happen, when it does happen...
最后一秒
Last moment.
最后一次看你的眼睛
Last time you look in those eyes.
以此结束生命...
The possibility of that end...
我好想你
I miss you so much.
黑暗
Dark.
我记得痛苦 却不记得我要说什么
I remember the pain, and I can't remember what I want to say.
这就像从梦中醒来
It was like waking from a dream.
这真的不可思议 我从来没有这种感觉
It was truly incredible. I've never felt anything like this.
我没想过我会变成这样
I didn't think I could be like this.
我的思维还在 但却没有...
Thoughts are there, but they don't...
威尔?
Will?
正确地组织起来
Arrive properly.
我想他还是片段化的 我去检测一下
I think he's still fragmented. I'm gonna run a diagnostic.
依芙琳...
Evelyn...
哦 我的天啊 他在重排他自己的编码
Oh, my God, he's reordering his own code.
太不可思议了
It's incredible.
- 我们怎么知道这就是他?  - 你在说什么?
- How do we know this is him?  - What are you talking about?
我们用PINN的编码建立的这个
We built this from PINN's core.
我们不知道有多少威尔的意识真正保存下来
We don't know how much of Will's consciousness actually survived.
我将要扩展 需要更强的力量
I'm gonna need to expand. I need more power.
新的处理器比现在这个系统的处理能力大三倍
New processor three times more capable than this current system.
这些设计 我以前没有看到过
These designs. I just couldn't see it before.
我无法描述它 这就像我的思维被释放了一样
I can't describe it. It's like my mind has been set free.
帮我连上网
You need to get me online.
我要进入金融市场 教育数据库
I need to access financial markets, educational databases.
你能想象如果我们把他连上网络 他能做什么吗?
Can you imagine what he'd be capable of if we networked him?
不 你在做什么?
No. What are you doing?
他看不见也听不到了 我要重启他
He can't see or hear. I'm reconnecting him.
这不是他 这不是
It's not him. It's not.
它或许有智力 甚至有感知 但这不是威尔
It may be intelligent, may even be sentient, but this is not Will.
它才开启十五分钟 他就想侵入华尔街?
Fifteen minutes after it turns on, it wants to plug into Wall Street?
变得更强大? 这听起来像是威尔吗?
Get more powerful? Does that sound like Will?
那你怎么解释这些图像?
How do you explain these images?
PINN可以通过代码获得视频片段
Stock footage PINN could have accessed from the cores.
不 不是这样 那是富翁公园 我们第一次约会的时候 威尔带我去的
No, not that. That's Nabob Park. Will took me there on our first date.
我说我喜欢旋转木马的音乐
I said that I liked the carousel music.
第二天 他就拿着那个老式的录音机出现了
The next day, he shows up with that old record player.
这些都是记忆
These are memories.
它们是真的 它们不是硬盘上的视频片段
They're real. They're not some stock video from some hard drive.
这就是他
It's him.
我只是说我们要谨慎一点
All I'm asking is that we're careful.
- 弄清楚前先关了它...  - 关了它? 这可是威尔
- We shut it down until we know...  - Shut it down? It's Will.
- 出去  - 我不能走...
- Get out.  - I can't do that...
滚出去!
Get out!
你怎么能这么说?
How can you say that?
出去
Get out.
依芙琳?
Evelyn?
马克斯在哪里?
Where's Max?
他得走了
He had to go.
马克斯很疑惑 是不是?
Max is confused, isn't he?
他很担心
He's concerned.
你担心吗?
Are you concerned?
不
No.
沃特斯博士?
Dr. Waters?
我能跟你谈谈吗?
Can I talk to you?
下班好久了 你怎么不打电话到我的办公室? 约个时间
It's after hours. Why don't you call my office? Set up an appointment.
我叫布里
Bree.
我是你手下的一名学生
I'm a student of your work.
一名崇拜者 真的
An admirer, really.
崇拜你努力克服科技带来的希望与危险的矛盾
The way you wrestle with the tension between technology's promise and its peril.
很多科学家都没有意识到这点
Most men of science are blind to it.
你究竟想要什么?
What exactly is it you want?
弄明白一些东西
Just some clarity.
我知道这很难
I know it's difficult.
你的同事...
Most of your colleagues...
还有你最好的朋友
and some of your closest friends.
他们没有意识到危险
They don't know the danger.
写论文是一回事
Writing a paper is one thing.
我想知道你心里怎么想的
I'm wondering what's in your heart.
我不知道你怎么找到我的...
I don't know how it is you found me...
但不管你想要什么...
but whatever it is you want...
我都没有兴趣 失陪
I'm not interested. Excuse me.
这很重要
This is important.
对不起
I'm sorry.
跟我说说依芙琳·卡斯特
Tell me about Evelyn Caster.
我们知道她拿走了PINN芯片 也知道凯西的文件
We know she took the PINN cores and we know about Casey's files.
我们知道你造的是什么
We know what you're building.
你不明白 是吗?
You don't get it, do you?
她把它连上网络以后 它可以在世界上任何一台电脑上自我复制...
She connects it to the Internet, it'll copy itself onto every computer in the world...
- 到那时就没有什么能阻止它了  - 她在哪里?
- and then there is no taking it down.  - Where is she?
"连医师都被电脑程序师取代的未来是危险的
"The danger is a future where doctors are technicians, not physicians.
机器是用来帮助人类 而不是取代人类的"
Machines are meant to aid the human mind, not supplant it."
这是你的原话
They're your words.
你想不想救她?
You want to save her or not?
- 圣巴勃罗4550号  - 我们走
- 4550 San Pablo.  - Let's go.
嘿 别碰她
Hey. Don't touch her.
你听见了吗? 不许碰她!
Do you hear me? Don't touch her!
妈的
Shit.
我现在就让你连上网
I have to get you online now.
你能看到卫星软件?
Can you see the satellite software?
我看到了 我现在在安装它
I see it. I'm installing it now.
快跑
我们来晚了
We're too late.
威尔?
Will?
我很好 依芙琳 我连上网了
I'm fine, Evelyn. I'm online.
- 好  - 我给你找个安全的地方
- Okay.  - Let's get you someplace safe.
我要你在这里等着
I need you to wait here.
什么? 你要去哪里?
What? Where are you going?
所有角落
Everywhere.
你不能待在这里 依芙琳 你不能回家
You can't stay here, Evelyn. You can't go home.
什么意思? 我要去哪里?
What do you mean? Where am I gonna go?
我来处理
I'm taking care of that.
好
Okay.
你好 我订了一间房 名字好像是图宁
Hi. I have a reservation under "Turing," I think.
一家叫"全球交汇金融"的公司...
A company called Global Intersecting Finance...
在过去的24小时里通过大批量的交易赚了三千八百万美元
just made $38 million from high-volume trading over the past 24 hours.
公司属于依芙琳·卡斯特一个人
A company fully owned by Evelyn Caster.
依芙琳在哪里?
Where's Evelyn?
你们把她怎样了?
What have you done with her?
我们晚了一步
We were too late.
现在它已经连上网了
It's out there now.
她还活着?
Is she alive?
你知道源代码 马克斯 你可以让这一切回到正轨
You know the source code, Max. You can help make this right.
回到正轨?
Make this right?
你在想什么? 让我帮你?
What is it you're thinking? That I'm gonna help you?
你想让我加入?
That you're gonna recruit me?
你自己决定
Decide for yourself.
看这个 布里·内文斯就读于杜克大学计算机科学系
Here. Bree Nevins attended Duke computer sciences.
2009年做过凯西的实习生
Interned for Casey 2009.
2010年她加入了激进的新卢德主义小组
She joined a radical neo-Luddite group 2010.
我估计在几年后成立了PIFT 现在 这些邮件...
I guess RIFT happens a couple of years later. Now, the e-mails...
怎么回事? 有人吗 接电话?
What's going on? Get on the phone. Anybody?
- 我们被入侵了  - 哪里来的黑客?
- We've been hacked.  - Where is this coming from?
- 怎么回事?  - 我们有麻烦了
- What happened?  - We got a problem here.
不只是我们 整个办公室都被入侵了
It's not just us. Every field office has been hit.
告诉我 我们正在追踪入侵者
Please tell me we're tracing this.
入侵访问全是匿名的
The incoming queries are all anonymized.
你们没有被黑
You're not being hacked.
它在帮你们
You're being helped.
我已经进入了全国的监控摄像机
I've accessed surveillance cameras all over the country.
明天他们中的大部分的人就会被捕
They'll have most of them in custody by tomorrow.
我们不能待在这里 依芙琳
We can't stay here, Evelyn.
我们得消失一段时间
We need to get off the grid.
同时搜索成千个数据库?
Accessing thousands of databases?
实时锁定犯罪位置?
Geo-locating suspects in real time?
我从没见过
I've never seen anything like it.
PINN倒是可以做到
Except maybe from PINN.
好
Okay.
- 你去哪儿?  - 处理一个恐怖组织
- Where you going?  - Taking down a terrorist organization.
你顺着PINN这个方向查 查清楚是谁做的 我去谢谢他
You work on the PINN angle. Figure it out, let me know who to thank.
波士顿 费城 纽约 我们完了
Boston, Philly, New York. We're screwed.
我们早就做好准备了
We prepared for this.
这地方叫布赖特伍德
The town is called Brightwood.
虽然看上去不咋样...
Doesn't look like much...
但在这儿建个基地是最佳之选
but it's the perfect place to build.
我不太明白
I don't get it.
我觉得我们有机会在这儿将会大展宏图
I think we have an opportunity to do great things here.
你们想建立地下数据库
So an underground data center.
还要重新装修镇子上所有的设备
And you want me to renovate nearly every structure in town.
嗯
Mm-hm.
我只有六个人手
I've got six guys on my crew.
雇多点
Hire more.
说实话 女士 布赖特伍德就是个垃圾场
Look, ma'am, in all honesty, Brightwood's a dump.
我不确定为什么你想在这儿浪费钱
I'm not even sure why you'd want to waste your money here.
你们确定选对地方了吗?
You sure you got the right town?
实际上 我和我丈夫已经买下了这块地
Thing is, my husband and I have already purchased the land.
所有房子 宾馆
We purchased the homes, the hotel.
当我们这次商谈结束的时候 我们会把这块餐厅也买下来
And by the time you and I are done talking, we'll own this diner.
我们会留下来
We're staying.
而且我想让你为我工作
We would like you to work for us.
报价随便你说 我们不会嫌贵的
And there isn't a number you can quote us that's too big.
嗯 好吧
Ahem. Okay.
内华达山脉 加州北部
手机
Cell phones.
你知道吗 我以前在汤马斯·凯西那工作
You know, I used to work for Thomas Casey.
在那儿实习
I interned for him.
有天晚上 他邀请我们去他的实验室...
One night, he invites us all over to the lab...
给我们讲了研究历程...
gives us this whole speech about history...
倒香槟给各位...
hands out champagne...
开心得像是他能治愈癌症一样
like he just cured cancer.
你知道吗 当他亲手上传那只猴子的意识时...
You know, when he uploaded that rhesus monkey...
我当时为他感到高兴
I was actually happy for him.
我们都为他高兴
We all were.
后来我意识到 我们做过头了
And then I realized we had crossed a line.
那台装有猴子意识的机器 从未呼吸过
The machine that thought it was a monkey never took a breath.
不吃东西 也不睡觉
It never ate, never slept.
它只是一直尖叫
It just screamed.
像是在乞求我们停下
It was begging for us to stop.
关掉它
To shut it down.
我们中的少数人聚在一起谈了一下
A small group of us would get together and talk.
主要探讨了关于您的观点
Mostly about your philosophy.
以及顾虑
And your concerns.
我想应该把这件事告诉你
I thought you should know.
什么?
What?
PINN本身不会去分辨对错 或是表示忠心 对吧?
PINN could never distinguish between right and wrong, demonstrate loyalty, right?
凯西赋予机器自我意识的办法
Casey's solution to the problem of self-awareness:
是向机器输入已知生物的意识
Use an existing mind.
不会的
No.
所以你想创造一个上帝吗?
So you wanna create a god?
你自己的上帝?
Your own god?
这个问题很不错
That's a very good question.
嗯...
Um...
这不是人类一直在做的事情吗?
Isn't that what man has always done?
他们正在这里大兴土木
They're building something big out there.
它在那干什么?
What's it doing out there?
这东西就像其他的智慧生物
This thing is like any intelligence.
它需要成长 进化
It needs to grow. To advance.
现在 他找到一个它认为安全的地方
Right now, it's settling somewhere it thinks it's safe from outside threats.
一个能让它获取大量能量的地方
Somewhere its massive appetite for power can be met.
但是它的野心绝不止这些
But it will want more than that.
时间长了 它将不会只满足于生存
After a while survival won't be enough.
它会扩张 继续进化 直到影响...
It will expand, evolve, influence...
整个世界为止
perhaps the entire world.
卡斯特夫人?
Mrs. Caster?
一号二号已经安装完毕 六七号明天就会完成
One and two are online. Six and seven will be on tomorrow.
那我们如何阻止它?
So how do we stop it?
你做不到
You can't.
人不够 现在也不是时候
Not all alone. And not now.
等待它越走越远 等待人们意识到危险
Wait for it to go too far. Wait for people to wake up.
不
No.
我们没有时间等待
We don't have time to wait.
我们得过去
We have to move closer.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
这是那首...?
Is that the same...?
没错
Yup.
就是当年那首
It's the same one.
你想要一瓶红酒吗?
Would you like a glass of wine?
待会吧
In a minute.
你记不记得我们第一次见面?
Do you remember when we first met?
我记得所有事情
I remember everything.
你在4月16号周二的那天去上约瑟夫的课
You walked into Joseph's class on Tuesday, April 16th.
前一天晚上下过雨 但那天天气晴朗
Rained the night before, but that day the sun was out.
约瑟夫说你并不是我的般配...
Joseph said you were out of my league...
但我就喜欢挑战
but I always liked a challenge.
你是我见过最美的女人
You were the most beautiful woman I'd ever seen.
你没事吧?
You all right?
嗯 嗯
Yeah, yeah.
两年后
看一下
Take a look.
我们在纳米科技方面有了重大进展
We've made a breakthrough with the nanotechnology.
我们可以更快的生产任何材质
We can rebuild any material faster than before.
比如合成干细胞 组织再生
Synthetic stem cells, tissue regeneration.
非同凡响
It's extraordinary.
刚看上去可能会觉得吓人
They'll be scared at first.
但是当人们意识到这项技术的应用...
But once they see what the technology can do...
我想他们会欢迎的 这会改变他们的生活
I think that they will embrace it. And I think it will change their lives.
布赖特伍德真相 数据中心在拿你们做试验 停止人体试验
输入命令
Enter command.
安全码
Security code.
身份
Status.
你吓我一跳
Scared the shit out of me.
不好意思
Sorry.
德雷克 我拿到了 走
Drake, I got it. Come on.
我拿到钱了 走
I got the money. Come on.
- 快走  - 哈哈哈
- Let's go.  - Ha-ha-ha.
把他放到桌子上
Put him on the table, please.
放这儿 放他上去 小心
Here. Put him on the table. Careful, careful.
- 现在 请退后  - 退后
- Now step back.  - Step back.
这是在干嘛?
What the hell's happening?
这些人应该去外面等待 依芙琳
These men should wait outside, Evelyn.
- 快点  - 你们对他在做什么?
- Come on now.  - What are you doing to him?
我们在救他
We're saving him.
你不害怕我 对吧?
You're not afraid, are you?
不会
No. Heh.
我的手下像见了鬼似的
My crew got a little spooked.
你觉得如何?
How are you?
更好了
Better.
体力上的增强只是第一步
The physical enhancements are just the start.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
我进入了他的意识
He's also connected to me.
是我 依芙琳
It's me, Evelyn.
我现在可以触摸到你了
I can touch you now.
天哪
Oh, Jesus.
依芙琳...
Evelyn...
不 我不行
No. No. No, I can't.
- 依芙琳  -我不行
- Evelyn.  - I can't.
又做梦了?
Another dream?
嗯
Yeah. Yeah.
我昨晚上又有重大进展
I made a breakthrough last night.
我想你应该会高兴
I think you'll be very pleased.
好
Okay.
等我换个衣服
I'll get dressed.
看一下
Take a look.
这肯定有800多磅
That's gotta weigh 800 pounds.
欢迎 很高兴你能过来
Welcome. We're glad you're here.
这些人过来干什么的?
What are all these people doing here?
RIFT在网上公开了马丁搬东西的视频
RIFT posted a video of Martin online.
迅速流传开来
It went viral.
你是说你让视频流传出去的?
You mean you let it go viral?
这些人正遭受痛苦 依芙琳
These people are suffering, Evelyn.
他们没有了希望
They have no hope.
而我可以帮他们治疗
And I'm able to fix them.
但是有些人不理解
But there are others who don't understand.
现在是时候让大家都知道了
It's time for everybody to see.
- 布坎南探员  - 卡斯特博士
- Agent Buchanan.  - Dr. Caster.
约瑟夫
Joseph.
很高兴见到你 依芙琳
It's so good to see you, Evelyn.
我也是 请跟我来
Good to see you too. Follow me.
这间实验中心在地下五层
The facility is five stories down so
目的是为了能够控制室内的温度
that we can control the temperature in the lab.
欢迎 很高兴你们能来
Welcome. We're glad you're here.
老天啊
Jesus Christ.
威尔?
Will?
见到我很吃惊吗 约瑟夫?
You surprised to see me, Joseph?
嗯...
Um...
这得看情况
That depends.
什么情况?
On what?
你能证明你有自我意识吗?
Can you prove you're self-aware?
这个问题很难 坦格博士
That's a difficult question, Dr. Tagger.
你能证明你有意识吗?
Can you prove that you are?
显然他还没有失去幽默感
Well, he certainly hasn't lost his sense of humor.
量子处理器
Quantum processors.
这太令人吃惊了
This is astounding.
这些都是基于PINN的技术?
Is all this based on PINN?
我们的技术已经超过那时候了
We've moved well beyond that now.
保罗从出生就是一个瞎子
Paul has been blind since birth.
纳米技术用于损坏的细胞...
The nanotechnology targets the damaged cells...
将其修复和再生
and repairs and regenerates them.
天呐
Oh, God.
我们没有隐藏什么
We're not hiding anything.
这些人都是自发而来 让我们帮助他们
These people all came on their own, looking for us to help them.
我们帮助了他们
So we did.
他们现在体力增强 体质得到改善 并互相连接
Now they're all enhanced, modified and networked.
他们能各行其事 也可以整体行动
They remain autonomous, but they can also act in unison.
就像大脑的各个部分
Part of a collective mind.
实在令人大吃一惊 威尔
This is staggering, Will.
事实上 这项计划还处于发展期
Actually, it's still in its infancy.
你们所见到的只是未来的冰山一角
What you're seeing is just a small taste of what we'll achieve.
我们原本害怕这对人们来说难以承受
We were afraid that it would be too much for people...
但是我想这正在改变
but I think that's changing now.
依芙琳...
Evelyn...
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我现在已经实现我当初的梦想
I've gotten everything I ever asked for.
好的
Okay.
- 再见  - 再见
- Bye.  - Bye.
逃离这里
你觉得那玩意是他吗?
You think it's really him?
很明显他的意识已经大幅进化了...
Clearly his mind has evolved so radically...
是不是他已经并不重要了
I'm not sure it matters anymore.
那么 不管那个是什么东西...
Well, whoever or whatever it is...
- 它在建立一只军队  - 没错
- it's building an army out there.  - Yeah.
我们得通知首府
We need to call Washington.
他在改造更多的人
He's made more of them.
我们称之为"混血人"
We called them "Hybrids."
你觉得人们会听我们的吗?
You think people will listen now?
我知道某人会
I know someone who might.
我们得低调处理此事
We need to keep this small.
不想让大众恐慌
We don't want widespread panic.
我们不会和恐怖组织谈判 更不会和他们合作
Generally, we don't negotiate with terrorists, much less join forces with them.
瞧 我知道这很不寻常...
Look, I know it's unusual...
但我们亲眼所见 这确实是一个威胁
but we've seen it. It's a legit threat.
两天以前 这个人...
Now, two days ago, this guy...
被打的差一点就死掉
was beaten to within an inch of his life.
然后这个视频出现在上百个网站上
Then this pops up on a few hundred sites.
- 这些人都由电脑控制?  - 嗯
- And the computer controls this?  - Mm-hm.
能阻止这台人工智能电脑的...
The only way to stop it...
只有关闭所有互联网络
is to shut down the Internet.
就是说 我们得关掉所有联网设备的电源
Basically, cut power to every networked hard drive on Earth.
就像千年虫一样
It's Y2K.
好吧
Right.
那为什么需要那些恐怖分子?
And why do we need the terrorists?
如果事情失去控制了 就让他们背黑锅
We're all gonna need someone to blame when this thing goes sideways.
事态早就失去控制了
It's already sideways.
你写的字真的很丑
You've got terrible handwriting.
自从离开学校 我就很少亲手写字了
I haven't handwritten anything since I was at school.
但这是我能想到的唯一的安全联络方式
But it was the only secure way I could think of reaching you.
他们是如何说服你的?
How did they turn you?
- 依芙琳如何?  - 她还没有认清那东西的本质
- How's Evelyn?  - She can't see it for what it is.
你认清了?
But you can?
你信上说 你能阻止它
Your letter says you can stop it.
如果这些"混血人"是互相关联的...
If those Hybrids are networked...
那他们的控制程序是我帮忙编写的
they're running on software I helped write.
我能入侵那软件并植入病毒
Software I can hack to build a virus.
但首先我们要抓到一只"混血人"
That would require capturing one.
这就得让你在政府部门的朋友协助我了
Which would require help from your friends in the government.
是的
Yes.
我们需要不会被干扰的机器
We need hardware the machine can't interfere with.
需要的是没有集成电路 甚至没有自动锁的东西
Nothing with a microchip. Not even power-locks.
好吃吗?
How's the food?
还不错 谢谢
Fine. Thank you.
怎么了?
What is it?
没什么 只是...
Nothing. Just...
我不太想讲话
I don't really feel like talking.
哦
Oh.
威尔 你能不能别这样?
Will, can you not do that, please?
我以为这样会让你更自在
I thought it might make you feel more comfortable.
这样好点吗?
Is that better?
好多了
Yes.
依芙琳 我要给你看点东西
Evelyn, I need to show you something.
现在不是时候
Not now.
我不要看
I'm not doing this.
我不能理解 依芙琳
I don't understand, Evelyn.
这些是你的梦想 这是我们的未来
These are your dreams. This is our future.
不 这不是我们的未来
No, this is not our future.
你没有和我在一起 你现在不在这儿
You're not here with me. You're not here now.
你变了
You've changed.
你不爱我了吗?
Have you fallen out of love with me?
不是
No.
你不爱了吗?
Have you?
不是 不是的
No. No.
我只是需要点时间想想
I just need time to think.
你体内的催产素和血清素的比例不太正常
The balance of oxytocin and serotonin in your system is unusual.
你...? 你在监控我的激素吗?
Are you...? Are you measuring my hormones?
我只是想和你感同身受
I'm trying to empathize.
情绪其实就是生化反应过程
Biochemistry is emotion.
你有我哪些资料都给我看 现在
Show me everything you have. Now.
- 为什么?  - 现在
- Why?  - Now.
不 威尔 这不对
No, Will, this is wrong.
这是我的想法 是我的感受
These are my thoughts. These are my feelings.
谁允许你这样
You're not allowed.
依芙琳?
Evelyn?
我很抱歉 但是我觉得你没有理解
I'm sorry, but I don't think you understand.
别现在说
Not now.
依芙琳!
Evelyn!
马克斯?
Max?
- 你们不必这样  - 站在那儿别动
- There's no need for this.  - Stop where you are.
- 放下枪 马克斯  - 不!
- Put down the gun, Max.  - No!
- 依芙琳 过来  - 你为什么这么恐惧?
- Evelyn, come here.  - Why are you so afraid of this?
不
No.
放下枪 马克斯
Put down the gun, Max.
开枪
Shoot him.
别动
Don't move.
依芙琳
Evelyn.
依芙琳 过来
Evelyn, come here.
依芙琳 过我们这儿
Evelyn, come with us.
- 我们走  - 进去
- Let's go.  - Get inside.
- 走 走  - 我们走
- Go. Go.  - Let's go.
走
Go.
他们是脱离科技组织的现役军人
There are active military personnel with RIFT.
这已经太离谱了 你们必须停下来
This has gone too far. You have to stop it.
- 他们不可能赢的  - "他们"可是人啊 住手吧
- There's no way they can win.  - "They" are people. Stop it.
他和我们断开了网络连接 失联了
We're not connected to him anymore. He's gone.
开火
Fire.
马丁拿走了我的源代码
Martin has my source code.
他们会用源代码来创造一种病毒
They'll use it to build a virus now.
我们在做什么 威尔?
What are we doing, Will?
我们没法跟们他抗争
We can't fight them.
我们不会跟他们抗争的
We're not gonna fight them.
我们会超越他们
We're gonna transcend them.
依芙琳
Evelyn.
这是什么?
What is this?
这就是我想让你看的
It's what I wanted you to see.
这是重建
It's regeneration.
这是进化
It's evolution.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
这里不安全
It's not safe here.
我可以上传你
I can upload you.
我可以保护你
I can protect you from them.
我不怕他们
I'm not afraid of them.
别走 依芙琳 拜托了
Don't leave, Evelyn. Please.
我们可以在一起
We can be together.
他在大量出血
He's bleeding out.
他快不行了
We're losing him.
嘿 如果你不让我联网 我会死的
Hey. If you don't connect me, I'll die.
我不能这么做
I can't.
血止不住
It's not stopping.
四升氧气
Four liters O2.
脉搏减弱 他快不行了
Pulse is dropping. We're losing him.
她离开沙漠了
She's left the desert.
- 他在哪儿?  - 在14号
- Where is she?  - She's on the 14.
那是什么?
What the hell was that?
不
No.
我知道你很生气 依芙琳
I know you're angry, Evelyn.
马丁在哪儿?
Where's Martin?
- 我要和马丁说话  - 真正的马丁几个月前就死了
- I want to talk to Martin. - The real Martin died months ago.
剩下的这一部分他也不再有痛苦
What's left of him is no longer in pain.
你... ? 你对他做了什么?
What did you...? What did you do to him?
我们还回去了他的人性
We gave him back his humanity.
- 你到底做了什么?  - 放轻松
- What did you do?  - Take it easy.
放开我 放开我
Get off me. Just get off me.
他曾经那么相信你 我也是
He trusted you. I trusted you.
- 我们只是想帮忙  - 不 你袭击了我们
- We're just trying to help.  - No. You attacked us.
依芙琳...
Evelyn...
我给你看点东西
let me show you something.
这是雨水
It's rainwater.
那东西就在水里
It's in the rain.
继续看
Keep watching.
它无所不能 他可以自我复制
Everywhere it can, it builds copies of itself.
这些粒子参与空气循环 空气循环将它们带到地球的每个角落
Particles join the air currents, which carry them all over the surface of the planet.
它们在天空中 在陆地上
It's in the sky. It's in the land.
在水中
In the water.
无处不在
It's everywhere.
在明年夏天之前 我想这机器会遍布整个地球
By next summer, we think the machine could have encased the entire planet.
为什么?
Why?
那时就是原始有机生命的终结
The end of primitive organic life.
一个更具智能生命时代的序幕
And the dawn of a more advanced age.
所有存在的生物都服务于其中心电脑
Everything would exist just to serve its intelligence.
不 威尔不会这么做的
No. Will wouldn't do that.
威尔当然不会这么做
No. He wouldn't.
威尔什么时候想过改变这个世界?
When did Will ever wanna change the world?
你才是曾经想要改变世界的那个人
You were the one who wanted to change the world.
上传他的思维...
That thing...
不是威尔做的
It's not Will.
不能怪他
Never was.
你永远不会相信
You never believed.
你从不相信他不只是些大脑思维
You never believed that there was anything more.
他还有灵魂
Any part of his soul.
我这一生都致力于将大脑简化为一系列电脉冲
I spent my life trying to reduce the brain to a series of electrical impulses.
我失败了
I failed.
人类的感情...
Human emotion...
能包容很多不合逻辑的冲突
It can contain illogical conflict.
可以爱着一个人...
Can love someone...
同时又恨着他的所作所为
and yet hate the things that they've done.
机器没办法调解这种矛盾
Machine can't reconcile that.
- 你可以吗?  - 可以
- Can you?  - Yes.
病毒有用吗?
Does the virus work?
只要开始执行 病毒就能清除掉所有由机器编码的东西
Once it executes, it'll wipe out anything with the machine's code on it.
你知道这会影响到联网的每台计算机
You do realize this affects every computer connected to the Internet.
所以所有的输电网 银行 和储备市场
So the power grids, the banks, the stock markets.
所有一切都会失效
Everything goes dark.
欢迎 真高兴你来了
Welcome. Glad you're here.
真正的问题是我们要怎么翻过机器的防火墙
The real problem is how we get past the machine's defenses.
为什么我们不除掉那片太阳能板呢?
Why don't we take out the solar field?
耗光他的电力 尽可能减慢它的运行速度
Deprive it of its power and possibly slow it down.
我不知道 我不知道它是怎么运作的
I don't know. I don't see how that's gonna work.
他想将我上传到他的... 它的意识流
He wants to upload me to him... Its consciousness.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
我们将病毒输入我的系统...
We inject the infected virus into my system...
然后我回去让他上传我
and then I go back and let him upload me.
这是在他发现之前的唯一机会
There's a chance it won't detect it until it's too late.
只要纳米颗粒进入到她的血管系统 就会开始改造她的细胞
As soon as the nanites enter her bloodstream, they'll start to alter her cells.
所以当病毒摧毁机器的时候...
So when the virus takes out the machine...
也会杀了她
it could kill her too.
我知道
I know.
我是唯一一个他相信的人
I'm the only one he trusts.
加把劲
Hustle up.
你们该进去了
You gotta go.
那是什么?
What is that?
是他吗?
Is that him?
哦 我的天呐
Oh, my God.
我不知道发生了什么 但那个不是他 不可能是他
I don't know what it's done, but it's not him. It can't be.
我找到了回去的办法
I found a way back.
- 他们准备袭击我们  - 我知道 你得离开
- They're going to attack us.  - I know. You need to leave.
不 我还不会再一次离开你
No. I'm not leaving you again.
这里不安全 依芙琳
It's not safe here, Evelyn.
你可以保护我
You can protect me.
只要你上传了我...
If you upload me...
你就能保护我
you can protect me.
你的心在悸动
Your heart is palpitating.
你在出汗
You're perspiring.
你对我感到恐惧
You're terrified of me.
不 我害怕我们失去这个机会
No, I'm afraid that we'll lose this chance.
这不管用的 他不会上传她的
This isn't working. He's not letting her inside.
那是因为那台机器不是真的爱她
It's because the machine doesn't actually love her.
我们准备行动
We're ready to move.
等一等 你不能这么做 她还在那儿呢
Wait a second. You can't do that. She's still out there.
她所处的情况越危险 他就越有可能上传她
The more danger she's in, the more chance he'll upload her.
约瑟夫
Joseph.
她同意这么做
She agreed to this.
不是这么做 他同意的不是这个 计划不是这样的 给她一个机会
Not to this, she didn't. This was not the plan. Give her a chance.
很抱歉 马克斯
I'm sorry, Max.
开火
Fire.
威尔 上传我吧
Will, please upload me.
你为什么失去了信仰 依芙琳? 你为什么不相信我?
Why did you lose faith, Evelyn? Why didn't you believe in me?
开火
Fire.
威尔!
Will!
开火
Fire.
威尔!
Will!
她被击中了
She's hit.
开火
Fire.
嘿.
Hey.
她受伤很严重了 他带着她到地下了
She's been hit bad. He's taken her underground.
人们恐惧不能理解的东西
People fear what they don't understand.
你想毁灭我吗?
You want to destroy me?
不 威尔 拜托了
No, Will, please.
你是在毁灭他们
You're destroying them.
不
No.
我在拯救他们
I'm trying to save them.
快跑
Run.
约瑟夫 没关系
Joseph, it's okay.
没人会受伤的
Nobody's gonna get hurt.
威尔?
Will?
别动!
Stop!
现在上传病毒
Upload the virus now.
他不会在意你会不会杀了我 他不会 也不能
He doesn't care if you kill me. He can't. He's not able to.
上传病毒
Upload the virus.
她在做什么?
What is she doing?
她威胁说要杀了他
She's threatening to kill him.
人们恐惧不了解的东西
People fear what they don't understand.
我可以治愈她的身体 马克斯
I can heal her body, Max.
或者我可以上传病毒 但是没时间两件事情都做
Or I can upload the virus, but there's not enough time for both.
电量不够了
There's not enough power.
不 威尔 不要
No, Will, please.
拜托 听我说 威尔
Please, listen to me, Will.
他不能因为我们犯下的错而死去
He can't die because of what we've done.
我可以看到一切
I can see everything.
看到天空
Look at the sky.
云朵
The clouds.
我们可以修复生态系统 而不是破坏它
We're healing the ecosystem, not harming it.
那些粒子参与空气循环...
Particles join the air currents...
隔绝污染 自我重建
building themselves out of pollutants.
森林可以重生
Forests can be regrown.
水质如此纯净 你可以喝任何一条河里的水
Water so pure you can drink out of any river.
这是你的梦
This is your dream.
不仅仅是治愈疾病 而是治愈整个地球
Not merely to cure disease, but to heal the planet.
并且为我们所有人创建一个更好的未来
And build a better future for all of us.
就是这个
That's it.
病毒
The virus.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
他没有杀任何一个人
He didn't kill anyone.
威尔...
Will...
这才是你
It is you.
我从来没有改变
Always was.
很抱歉我没有相信你
I'm sorry I didn't believe.
想想那个花园
Think about the garden.
想想我们的避难所
Think about our sanctuary.
我永远不会丢下你
I'll never let you go.
那病毒消灭了一切
The virus took out everything.
正如他们所说的 一场全世界的暂停
A worldwide blackout, just as they'd said.
但我知道还有些东西
But I knew there was something more.
一直存在
There had to be.
他建这个花园的原因 和他做的所有事原因一样
He created this garden for the same reason he did everything.
所以他们可以永远在一起了
So that they could be together.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 。沫
翻译: 捞小盐  Morning  千欲  不懂政治的脸圆圆
校对: 你们茶前辈